and amen if you love me
keep my ways that is a
that's a powerful song
that
really prepares us for
um
the message today
and uh today i'm gonna be talking about
the law of god
uh and the question as to whether
the commandments still stand
or are they done away with and um
if uh you're listening and watching this
for the first time you're gonna learn
some things that you may not have
learned before
um because i'm gonna i'm gonna
try to make it plain today that there
are a lot of people that are confused
over this issue
because they don't understand the
context remember what i just said
they do not understand the context
so i'm going to invite you to pray with
me
and then we're going to get into this
presentation and uh we're going to be
looking at some scripture that's gonna
give us a definitive answer uh go ahead
and share this link with someone that
you believe needs to see this
and um
let's go ahead and pray all right let's
do that now heavenly father
we thank you
lord for
your love towards us
and we thank you lord for your desire
to see us walk in truth
and so lord speak to us now
show us
your truth from your word is our prayer
in jesus name we ask it
amen
and amen
all right
so
i want to start with the
the uh idea of
the law of god or actually let me let me
do it this way i want to first talk
about the
the moral crisis
that we often hear about that is
happening in our nation
uh and depending on where you are in the
world in the world
okay
um you can go online and find any number
of articles
uh talking about the erosion of
america's foundation and usually this is
from the perspective of christians right
christians are the ones that are
typically talking about the moral
decay destroying america i'm just
showing you a couple of articles here
uh here's one from the uh from barnard
research the end of absolutes america's
new moral code and they're kind of
talking about how
you know people are just making up their
own morals right nothing is absolute
anymore
um christians be cry this all the time
uh
we we see another one here survey
departure from god is cause of america's
moral
decline
right um
all of these are issues that that we are
facing here's one on the theology of of
of abortion right um the commandment
thou shall not kill
thou shalt not kill and that one is
really really i mean that's a present
issue we're dealing with right now and
uh
for the christian
the argument is
right the commandment says thou shalt
not kill
and and we ought to obey the word of god
and this is why there's such a moral
decline because no one is listening or
obeying the word of god uh anymore
here we have another one 10 reasons why
it's wrong to take the life
of unborn children and you could see the
first one
given there and we're just going to look
at this very quickly is god commanded
thou shalt not murder and exodus chapter
20 is quoted and so
uh it is
it is a serious issue right for
christians that i'm speaking
specifically to christians today um i
mean everyone is welcome to listen but
the question again is is this what is
the position that a christian should
take towards the law of god especially
as it relates
to what we call the moral
decline that is happening in the world
well let me suggest to you that
while the christian world is is you know
kind of looking at how nobody's
following god anymore and you know
people are turning their backs on the
bible people are turning their backs on
on the word of god and coming up with
their own morals
may i suggest
that perhaps part of
the reason for that
is actually it actually has to do
with
christianity and its position on the
word of god itself
let me say that again
could the reason that
that people are turning away from
the word of god and from
uh uh you know god's absolute morals
could the reason be because of what they
are seeing within christianity itself
now i know that sounds like whoa kind of
harsh but i need you to follow this
because i'm going to show you something
let's go back to the screen
and i want you to notice what romans
chapter 2 verse 21
through 24 around 24 says notice what it
says here thou therefore which teaches
another
teaches thou not thyself
thou that preaches a man should not
steal
does thou steal
thou that says a man should not commit
adultery does thou commit adultery
thou that aborist idols dost thou commit
sacrilege
thou that maketh thy boast of the law
through breaking the law dishonors thou
god
and now look at this next verse
for the name of god is blasphemed among
the gentiles through you
as it is written
let me pause for a second
back in paul's day
paul was saying listen
because of the of the hypocrisy of
the professed people of god
the gentiles are blaspheming the name of
god
so let me give you an example of what i
mean
so if we were to ask you know the
typical christian
okay um
why should abortion
be outlawed and the response is gonna be
because the commandment says thou shalt
not kill and why is our country you know
going into more decline oh because
they're not obeying the word of god
they're not obeying the moral absolutes
of god you hear christians say this
without blinking an eye it's a natural
response right what are they doing that
they shouldn't be doing and the answer
is they
are not keeping god's moral law yet
the very same christians if you turn
around and ask them hey
as a christian
should you keep the commandments and
they will begin to quote verses like
this notice with me on the screen
ephesians chapter 2
and verse 8 it says for by grace are ye
saved through faith and that not of
yourselves it is the gift of god not of
works
lest any man should boast now hold on a
second
i i just
i just inquired
why do you think
america is on a moral decline and the
answer was
america's on a moral decline because
they are not keeping
the law of god they are not keeping the
moral absolutes of god and yet when the
question is turned around and asked
should you keep the law as a christian
then all of a sudden
you get a totally different response
ah we're not saved by works we're saved
by
faith or how about this one
how about this one
ephesians chapter 2 and verse 15
uh uh having abolished in his flesh the
enmity
even the law of commandments contained
in ordinances for the makings himself of
twain one new man so making peace
blotting out the handwriting of
ordinances that was against us which was
contrary to us and took it out of the
way nailing it to the cross and they'll
respond listen
we don't have to keep the law because it
was nailed to the cross but i want you
to understand for the secular mind how
confusing that sounds
on one hand
abortion should be outlawed because the
bible clearly says thou shalt not kill
it's one of the commandments and exodus
chapter 20 is quoted
you guys you heathen you
atheists you non-believers you gentiles
you you people that are not of god
you need to keep the law
but when the very same question is posed
to the believer oh
the law has been nailed to the cross
we don't have to keep the commandments
it's been done away with that's the old
testament
so i want you to understand the
confusion and again my question is could
could the reason that the world
has turned away or or does not
acknowledge the law of god is because
the church
does not acknowledge the law of god
wow
while
telling the world that the world needs
to acknowledge the law of god
we need moral absolutes we need the law
of god we need god we need people to
understand that god's word does not
change but here's the issue guys because
those two verses that we just read
they they sound like what people say
right like yeah the text clearly says
that we're gonna go back and look at
that
but we gotta ask ourselves the question
is the bible contradicting itself right
is that a fair question would you say
that's a fair question is the bible
contradicting contradicting itself does
the bible have a double standard and is
that the reason why christians also have
a double standard hey
thou shalt not kill stop abortion
or
but at the in the same breath ah we're
not under the law we're under grace
the law has been nailed to the cross the
law has been done away with
that's confusion
okay so so let's see does the bible
contradict itself well
look at jesus's own words
jesus said in luke 18 20 thou knowest
the commandments do not commit adultery
do not kill do not steal do not bear
false witness honor thy father and thy
mother so in jesus mind the commandments
still stood how about john 14 21 he that
has my commandments and keepeth them he
is that loveth me and he that loveth me
shall be loved of my father and i will
love him and manifest myself unto him so
again jesus seems clear that the
commandments still stand notice
revelation 22 14. it's the last book of
the bible and here it says blessed are
they that do his commandments
that they may have right to the tree of
life and may enter in through the gates
into the city how about revelation 12 17
and the dragon that is satan was wroth
with the woman which represents the
church and went to make war with the
remnant of her seed which do what keep
the commandments of god and have the
testimony of jesus christ how about
first john 3 4 whosoever committed sin
transgresses also the law for sin
is what everyone it is the transgression
of the law so
we see here pretty clearly that the law
of god
in in some place in the bible it appears
to stand but in other places we just
read that the handwriting of ordinances
was blotted out that we're not under the
law we're under grace
what
what's going on here
how about first john 5 2 by this we know
that we love the children of god when we
love god and keep his commandments for
this is the love of god that we keep his
commandments and his commandments are
not grievous what in the world is going
on let me say this to you
that i believe
that the majority of christians
are just confused
and i'm not saying that in a mean
derogatory way i'm saying that in a way
that you know there are christians who
who want to know truth
and
they can't make sense of how the bible
in one place can say the law of god
still stands but in another place it
says we're not under the law and the law
has been nailed to the cross and so in
in in being unable to
to mend these two so that they make
sense
you'll find them you'll find a lot of
christians will jump from one position
depending on who they're talking to to
another position depending on who
they're talking so when they're talking
to the world ah the bible says thou
shalt not kill and the law of god is
unchangeable and when is god ever these
are not ten commandments these are ten
these are not ten suggestions they're
ten commandments right you hear things
like that
but you turn around and ask these same
christians do you need to keep the
commandments and they're like oh no no
no no the commandments have been done
away with uh we're not under the old
covenant anymore we're under the new
covenant and they're not
these people are not intentionally
trying to be deceptive at least i don't
think i just think that there are a lot
of christians who don't understand the
context what did i say everyone they
don't understand the
context and maybe it's because they
haven't been taught it maybe it's
because they that what they're hearing
from the pulpits is not making sense but
they're just going along with it anyway
so
what we're going to do
uh in this study in this message is
we're going to understand the context so
that you can step back and see the big
picture and really get this okay that's
what we're after we're after
understanding so no matter who you are
no matter what christian background you
are from
context is extremely important right we
don't want to contradict the bible or
worse yet seem like hypocrites by
telling the world thou shalt not kill
it's a commandment you need to stop
abortion but at the same time we're
turning around and saying the law of god
has been nailed to the cross we don't
need to keep it anymore because jesus
came that doesn't quite add up
okay
so are you all ready
put a one in the chat if you're ready
you're all right pastor let's let's get
the context let's try to understand all
right so let's do that we're gonna go to
genesis chapter one we're gonna go back
to the beginning we're gonna go to
genesis one
and we're gonna begin to paint a picture
that is hopefully by the grace of god
gonna make this
very simple and hopefully unforgettable
you will never be confused about this
again no matter what text you read in
the bible that seems to be saying one
thing you'll be like oh
i get that now oh i get this now all
right watch so genesis chapter 1
and verse 27 heavenly father again we
pray that you give us understanding help
me to make this simple lord help me to
make this plain
in jesus name amen
so when we go to genesis chapter 1
beginning with verse 27 the bible says
here so god
created man in his own image
in the image of god created he him male
and female created he them
and god blessed them
and god said unto them be fruitful and
multiply and replenish the earth
and subdue it
replenish the earth and subdue it so
let's pause right here for a second in
the beginning we know that god created
mankind and he gave them a commission to
what
be fruitful and multiply right so man is
supposed to cover the earth with with
other
men right with human beings with
offspring be fruitful and multiply
we also know that god tells adam and eve
or adam in the garden
genesis 2 16 the bible says and the lord
god commanded the man saying of every
tree of the garden thou mayest freely
eat but of the tree of the knowledge of
good and evil thou shalt not eat of it
for in the day that thou eat is thereof
thou shalt surely die so we know that
god commands man listen donate from that
tree of knowledge of good and evil
because if you do so
you are going
to die you're going to die well we know
that in the very next chapter of the
bible in genesis chapter 3
the bible says
speaks about this serpent that deceives
adam and eve it's the devil right in
genesis 3 1 the bible says now the
serpent was more subtle than any beast
of the field which the lord god had made
and he said unto the woman yea has god
said you shall not eat of every tree of
the garden and the woman said unto the
serpent we may eat of the fruit of the
trees of the garden but of the fruit of
the tree which is in the midst of the
garden god has said you shall not eat of
it neither shall you touch it lest you
die
and the serpent said unto the woman you
shall not surely die for god does know
that in the day you eat thereof then
your eyes shall be opened and ye shall
be as gods knowing good and evil and
when the woman saw that the tree was
good for food and that it was pleasant
to the eyes on the tree to be desired to
make one wise she took the fruit thereof
and did eat and gave also to
gave also unto her husband with her and
he did eat
and we know that this is how
sin entered right this is how sin
entered okay
so
when sin enters when sin enters
uh adam and eve are now under a new
power
at that moment
who is now ruling mankind
just put it in the chat for me please
who is now ruling mankind the moment
that eve as well as adam eat from the
tree whose are they who do adam and eve
now
rightfully belong to
very good very good they are now satan's
they belong to him now let me ask you a
question
as they
left as it were
as they begin to be fruitful and
multiply
who do all that offspring
now belong to
who do all the offspring now belong to
right all that offspring that's going to
be born they would belong to
satan
okay so just follow this if god had not
intervened then all the offspring of
adam and eve would belong to satan now
here's what we find is very interesting
go with me back to the screen and i want
you to notice romans 5 verse 12. the
bible says wherefore
as by one man
sin
entered into the world and death by sin
and so death passed upon all men
for that all have sinned all right come
back come back
so
we know that when adam and eve sinned
they had given themselves over to the
devil and then giving themself over to
the devil their offspring were also
given over to the devil because
through their sin
all humankind was guilty because all
humankind were in their loins
did that make sense put a one in the
chat if that makes sense if you're
following me so far
all right so now if
if we're keeping track right adam and
eve the only two human beings on the
planet now belong to
satan
and
how many people does god have on the
planet as his own
zero
zero none adam and eve have now given
themselves over to death they've given
themselves over to satan for him to rule
them
now
it is in that context that i want you to
check out genesis 3 15.
genesis 3 15 notice what it says on the
screen genesis 3 15
so god after
giving adam his punishment and eve her
punishment he then turns to the serpent
and he begins to speak his punishment
and i want you to notice what genesis 3
15 says
genesis 3 15 reads god's speaking and i
will put enmity
between thee and the woman
and between
now watch this guys
thy seed
and her seed
it shall bruise thy head
and thou shalt bruise his heel all right
let's come back here
so notice this
god says i'm going to put enmity between
your seed and the woman's seed now what
does that indicate
what does that indicate
who would be
the devil's seed
and i want you all to think with me okay
who would be the devil's seed
who would that represent
i want to see if y'all put it in chat
just want to see if you can get who
would that represent who would the
devil's seed or the devil's offspring as
it were represent
you are for the devil who would that be
very good rick it would be everybody it
would be mankind
it would be unbelievers very good
carolina it would be unbelievers sergio
says cain very good rav says us hmm
wow
us
let me ask you which one of us were born
followers of christ
none of us
none of us so watch what god is saying
here god is literally saying to satan
look you may have just taken over all of
humanity but when god says i will put
enmity between the woman's seed and your
seed he has just spoken into existence
the fact that he is about to redeem a
people out of satan's camp
put a one in the chat if that if if you
just caught that
you just got adam and eve okay and and
and
in them is the whole human family but
i'm letting you know that there's gonna
be enmity between your seed and
her seed god has just spoken a gospel
promise there i'm about to redeem
humanity
and that redemption is going to be
evident in her seed and and particularly
in one individual who is that seed that
that he's ultimately talking about he's
talking about
jesus christ
are you with me so far
i know you're like pastor we're supposed
to talk about the law trust me we're
gonna get there but i need you to
understand genesis 3 15 first
okay no
no
what is enmity
so so the the the text said i will put
enmity between
your seed and her seed so enmity beloved
is something that is placed
in between
two individuals or two groups to keep
them
separate
rav very good enmity is division you're
either on this side
or that side so god says i'm gonna put
division between
my seed my people right
through the woman
and through your people please put a one
in the chat if you understand that
i'm gonna put division
between my people
those who choose to follow me
and those who choose to follow you
now i got a question for you so think of
it think of it like division
enmity is division
you might think of it of something as
something like a partition
it's opposition it's to be against
right that's what enmity is i'm gonna
put something between my people and your
people and it's gonna serve as a buffer
now watch this a lot of you are saying
ah mutual hatred but let me ask you a
question is this enmity is it a good
thing or a bad thing
we're gonna take a vote right now
put put
just go ahead and put the word bad or
good
let's see what you put in the chat is it
a bad thing or a good thing
all right so i see some saying good i
see some saying bad well
let me just tell you
that if god put it there
god said i will put enmity then it's a
good thing
now watch this guys god is putting
enmity now now now what he's doing is he
giving is he giving satan seed enmity
is god
putting a
a a desire to stay apart
is he putting that in bad people in
people who are like i'm uh you know i am
satan seed is that what he's doing
no no no no no beloved god never puts
enmity against righteousness
god is not the author of making bad
people hate good people or bad people
not want anything to do with good people
that's not what god does because god's
trying to save how many
he's trying to save everybody
so the enmity he's putting there
is in his own people
i'm going to create a division that's
going to separate my people who i'm
gathering by the way who i'm redeeming
from your camp
amen
amen i'm gonna put a a barrier of
protection i'm gonna put a
a a a partition i'm gonna put a dividing
wall between my people and your people
and this is going to keep my people safe
for a reason for a purpose
so so number one the bible says that he
was going to put enmity in other words a
buffer between his people and satan's
people by the way i want you to know
this on the screen no note the text
he's gonna put enmity note that first
thing
james 4 4 you're adulterous and
adulteresses no you're not that
friendship of the world is enmity with
god whosoever therefore shall be a
friend of the world is the enemy of god
so see that
enmity means that you're
for for something and against something
you're on one side or the other there's
a dividing wall between you and that
other thing
all right all right so let's keep moving
someone said
who's the devil seed is that us
let me let me get your answer from this
romans 3 23 all have sinned and come
short of the glory of god so let me ask
you a question who was a devil seed
who was a devil seed
everybody
everybody but god said i'm gonna
separate a people out of that seed now
please just follow along don't even
worry about the law right now because
when we get to it you're gonna be like
ah you pastor you have to say anymore i
get it now so just follow along follow
along
so so enmity god says i'm gonna put
enmity
i'm gonna draw out a people
right
out of
your
offspring and they're gonna be my people
and i'm gonna separate them i'm gonna
put a dividing wall between my people
and your people
those who follow me and serve me versus
those who follow you and serve you now i
want you to note this again isaiah 59
verse 1 behold the lord's hand is not
shortened that he cannot save neither is
this here heavy baby cannot hear but
your iniquities have separated between
you and your god and your sins have hid
his face from you that he will not hear
your hands are defiled with blood
and your fingers with iniquity your lips
have spoken lies your tongue has
muttered perverseness none called it for
truth nor any plea for truth they trust
in vanity and speak lies they conceive
mischief and bring forth iniquity let me
rephrase it this way all
all
who
are against god
because of their sins
are the devil's offspring remember how
jesus said in the book of uh in the in
the in the gospels when he's talking to
the pharisees that you are of your
father the devil and his works you do
you of your father the devil so that
gives you an idea the devil's seed would
be all the wicked god the woman's seed
will be those who
come out of that group to serve god okay
so
we see that god gives a a a a in fact no
no let me let me go back here let me go
back here um
no we can do that genesis 3 21 unto adam
also and to his wife did the lord god
give coats of skin and cold them this is
his act of redemption
this is his act of redemption
right when he when he gives them these
coats of skins how do they get these
coats of skins an animal had to die
so adam and eve are the first per people
redeemed
under the gospel umbrella
did you catch that
adam and eve are the first people
redeemed under the gospel umbrella and
how do we know that because when god
clothed them
he had an animal had to die in order to
cover them
to cover their nakedness
are y'all with me so far
okay
not only does the prophecy say that he
would put a enmity between his people
and god's people but it goes on to say
that that this seed would bruise the
head of the serpent
okay so number one i will put enmity
number two i'm gonna bruise the my son
christ is going to defeat or bruise the
head of the serpent right so y'all get
that and all of you are very familiar
with this but i'm about to show you
something now
you're about to see something now
because there's a third part of this
prophecy
you
see in
defeating watch this
in defeating the enemy that is in
defeating christ
he would then
remove
the enmity
okay
now i know that y'all are not getting
this you may not get this right now
remove the enmity what he put it there
watch this he put the enmity there
because of what satan did
now he says uh so i'm gonna put enmity
my son is gonna bruise your head that
means i'm gonna defeat you and then
we're gonna see that as a result of
saying being defeat satan being defeated
he will in essence remove
the enmity
now
i know what you're thinking right now
why would god
remove
the enmity
why would he get rid of the enemy so
hold on
we're about to lay this down
okay
so we know that this is genesis right we
see here we're looking for three things
number one he's gonna put enmity number
two he's gonna destroy the the devil and
then number three he's going to remove
the enmity not having proven to you
about removing the enmity all i've shown
you from scripture is that he put enmity
and that he would bruise the head of the
serpent okay
so we know that in leviticus chapter 20
uh chapter 22 chapter 20 verse 22
that um
god
has called israel out of egypt
he has separated a people for himself
out of it out of the world it's a
peculiar people and we read elizabeth 20
verse 22 you shall therefore keep all my
statues and all my judgments and shall
do them that the land whether i bring
you to dwell therein spew you not out
and you shall not walk in the manner of
the nations which i cast out before you
for they committed all these things and
therefore i abort them watch this but
i've said unto you
you shall inherit the land and i will
give it unto you to possess it a land
that flows with milk and honey i'm the
lord your god which have done what
separated you from other people
separated you
from
other people
let me just throw another one in here
very quick first kings 8 53 for thou did
separate them from among all the people
of the earth to be thy inheritance as
thou stake is by the hand of moses thy
servant when that brought our fathers
out of egypt so let's just recap here
what do we see god doing here is god has
god separated for himself a people is
there the offspring of the woman is
there the seed of the woman and also the
seed of the world yes or no put a one in
the chat if you're following so far okay
i get it god separated his people israel
from the rest of the world put a one in
the chat if you get that thus far
i'm following you pastor i i i i got
this yes
he separated his people right
and and and now you've got two distinct
lines you had them before israel right
you had the sons of god in genesis 6 and
the daughters of men in genesis 6 just
when the flood was happening so we've
always seen that line cain and abel
yeah
right you can just just go down the line
and trace the lineage of of those who
serve god and those who serve say so the
seed of the woman and the seed of the
devil king would have been the seed of
the devil yes
okay
so now god's got a whole group of people
it's a nation
israel and he separates them we see that
in the text
now
i want you to notice
what he does next
in exodus 34 verse 28 watch this watch
this all right now now y'all can get
ready now y'all can get ready in exodus
34 28
speaking of moses he was there with the
lord 40 days and 40 nights he did
neither eat bread nor drink water and he
wrote upon the tables the words of the
covenant the ten
what everyone
the ten
commandments
the ten commandments okay
so
god here is now giving the children of
israel a law
what is that law
the law
is called the ten command not the twelve
commandments
not the fifteen commandments
not the six hundred commandments but the
ten commandments and they're written on
stone now what i want you to understand
about these commandments well first of
all the most important thing i need you
to understand is this
these ten commandments
thou shalt not kill right thou shalt not
commit adultery thou shalt not lie thou
shalt not steal honor thy father and thy
mother thou shall have no other gods
before me thou shalt not take the name
of the lord in vain remember the sabbath
keeper holy these commandments listen
carefully
describe
sin
they are the description
of sin put a one in the chat if that
makes sense to you the ten commandments
are the description of sin if you kill
it is sin if you lie it is sin if you
commit adultery it is sin
if you if you are covet it is sin the
ten commandments describe
what sin is this is why the bible says
in first john 3 4 whosoever committed
sin transgresses also the law for sin is
a transgression of the law and this is
why romans 3 verse 20 says therefore by
the deeds of the law shall no flesh be
justified in inside for by the law is
the knowledge of sin so in other words
what paul is saying here is that the
only purpose that the law serves that
when he's talking specifically about the
ten commandments now is to tell you what
sin is
remember paul said i had not known uh uh
um what is it i have not known uh lust
except the laws of thou shalt not covet
he's saying listen the law tells me what
sin is
the law is the description
of
sin
so so the children of israel were
commanded to to
not sin to keep the commandments of god
don't lie don't steal etc okay y'all
good with that so far
now i'm gonna introduce you to something
else and i want you to watch this
in the minute what happened to someone
sin what happened if someone
sinned that's the question right how did
god deal with sin so the commandments
only reveal okay you're in the guilty
category right you've sinned now how
does how did god deal with sin
in the old testament
so i want you to watch again i want you
to notice what's on the screen
luke four verse one leviticus four verse
one i'm sorry and the lord spake unto
moses saying speak unto the children of
israel saying if a soul shall sin
through ignorance against any of the
commandments of the lord concerning
things which ought not to be done and
shall do against any of them
if the priests and so they give they go
through and save as a priest if it's a
ruler etc right
and this is just an example if the
priesthood is anointed to do sin
according to the sin of the people then
let him bring for his sin which he has
sinned a young bullock without blemish
unto the lord
for a sin
offering
so let me ask you a question
what happened if a person sinned in the
old testament
what would they have to do
they would have to perform
a ceremony
and that ceremony was a sacrifice
right it's a ceremony it's kind of it's
a ritual that you go through
in order to be forgiven for what
breaking the law
what law so watch this there was a law
so there's the law that describes sin
okay there's a law that describes sin
and then there is something else that
was done
when one broke that law and look again
at what the bible says hebrews 9 22
almost all things are by the law purge
with blood and without shedding of blood
is no remission so let me ask you a
question
what law is paul talking about here
and almost all things are by the law
purged with blood
what law is he talking about when you
read the ten commandments do you do you
see anything about
the need to bring blood or the need to
shed blood in order to forgive sins
no there's nothing in the ten
commandments that talks about sacrifice
right or how you're forgiven for your
sins it's just the description of sin
but there was another law given that was
what we will call the prescription for
sin
this is the ceremonial law
the ceremony what is the ceremony that
is necessary to carry out if one has
sinned ah if you sin if you break the
law
then
the response is the remedy is the cure
is
the ceremonial law
you have to sacrifice an animal
put a one in the chat if that's clear
for you right now
the the ceremonial law
the the moral law
was the description or is the
description of sin
the ceremonial law was the prescription
for sin
oh i sinned i want to be forgiven okay
well this is what you need to do
are y'all good so far
okay excellent very good very good so
let's keep moving so
here is a question now
um
that's a good thing god has provided for
his people there's a there's a issue and
that is sin but god has provided for his
people the remedy for sin let me ask you
a question what about the devil seed
what about the devil's seed
let's say that they did something wrong
could they walk up into the camp of
israel and be like man
only way to get forgiveness
is to just like
you know
go offer up an animal could they do that
yes or no
so y'all are already jumping ahead of me
y'all are already seeing this
could they do that
no they could not do that so let me try
to phrase it this way
there was something blocking them
from gaining access to the cure for sin
put a fire emoji in the chat if you just
got that
put put a one whatever you need to put
in the chat just put that there for me
so i know you got that there was
something there was a
a wall a
a series of of things that that
separated them from having access to the
cure so remember god says i'm going to
put enmity so that i'm going to separate
my people from the world the world is
not going to be able to just to just you
know find
their they're going to be separate from
what my people have access to
there's there's your seed and there's my
seed
my people
when they sin they're gonna have a cure
for that sin
but your people when they sin
they have no cure
is all hope lost
for the devil seed watch watch follow
these guys follow this watch this
is there a way that they could get
access that this the the these you know
what they what the jews would call
gentiles right or or or the heathen
right or the devil's seed was there a
way that they could have access to gain
access to the cure for sin
which in the old testament was sacrifice
the shedding of blood
i want you to notice what exodus 12 43
says this is the passover the lord
speaking about here the bible says here
this and the lord said unto moses unto
moses and aaron this is the ordinance of
the passover there shall no stranger eat
thereof now i need you to get this right
the passover is the very first festival
of the jewish year
no stranger was allowed to eat the
passover so let me ask you a question
let me ask you a question let's just
come back here real quick
let's say that you were a stranger
let's say that you were a stranger right
you're uh you know you're an egyptian
and you're like man
i just feel this weight of guilt on me
but
and i believe that the god of israel
can can
save me from that weight of guilt
but wait a minute
i can't eat of the passover
i can't get access
to the
ceremonial system
that cures
my guilt this is the old testament i
can't get rid of this i can't get access
there's it's like i would like to but
there is this wall and the wall says if
you're not an israelite you can't enter
in put a one in the chat if you get that
there is this this separation that
almost feels like enmity like man does
god have something against me
why can't i have access
all right let's keep moving let's let's
go back to the text exodus 12 44 but
every man's servant that is brought for
money when thou has circumcised them
then shall he wait what when you have
what hold on hold on
a foreigner and a hired servant shall
not eat thereof
in one house shall be eaten thou shalt
not carry forth out of the flesh abroad
out of the house neither shall you break
a bone thereof watch this verse 47 and
all the congregation of israel shall
keep it now verse 48 and when a stranger
adjourns with thee and will keep the
passover to the lord
let all his males be circumcised
and then
let them come near
and keep it
and he shall be as one that is born in
the land for no
uncircumcised person shall eat thereof
all right y'all
put a one in the chat
what was the one thing
that those who were afar off meaning the
devil seed right the devil seed they
have been separated by enmity right god
has put enmity something that is against
a stranger not against his people that
is against the stranger ah man look at
israel they're getting saved over there
they got salvation over there i want to
get in but i can't there's this wall
there's this wall of laws that per that
that exclude me
from getting access to the cure
but you know god is merciful right
he says listen
if if you who are on the devil's seed
truly want salvation then
the answer is
in order to get access to the cure
right the sacrifices that bring
forgiveness in the old testament in
order to get access you must be what
everyone come on put it in the chat
y'all you must be what
circumcised and then you can come near
remember that phrase y'all then you can
come near so in order for them to come
because they were far
enmity
there's a distance there's a separation
this thing is against you but if you
want to come near
man you're going to have to go through
something quite painful
you're going to have to be circumcised
as an adult who
not only you but your whole family of
men that's what the text says let him
and all the males in his family be
circumcised whoa
man that was difficult
watch this let's keep moving let's keep
moving i want you to see this so so so
note here then in ephesians chapter 2
verse 11 wherefore remember that you
being timed past
gentiles in the flesh who are called
uncircumcision
by that which is called the circumcision
in the flesh made by hands that without
that at that time you are without christ
being aliens from the commonwealth of
israel and strangers from the covenant
of promise having no hope and without
god do you see this
let me read that again
wherefore
remember
rem oh okay
hold on a second y'all
give me one second
i need to do something here so
let me just
let me just do this
and i'm going to share some text with
you
that um
that actually
didn't have up here let's let's do this
let's do this
uh
okay
so i want you to watch this guys i want
you to watch this
so so
here's a question let me go back to the
slide here's a question
how was this against satan's seed
right that's the question how was this
this law of circumcision against the
seed of satan well number one you could
not get access to the cure unless you
are circumcised so so let me let me go
back to this you understand that the
cure
and the prescription for sin and the
description for sin are two different
things
one law describes sin the other law
points you to the cure for sin and
that's under the old testament
are you are you catching what i'm saying
okay so so the question again is how is
this
against or in opposition almost how was
this difficult
for the
for the gentile for the person that was
not an israelite well number one notice
notice on the screen number one
you could not get access to the cure
unless you were circumcised
number two
the gentiles would have to journey to
the temple
to get access
in other words if you were far away from
from the temple like you lived in a
totally different nation
the only way for you to get salvation
you couldn't just be in your house and
be like well
uh let me offer up a lamb
no no no no you have to go to the temple
watch watch leviticus 4 4 he shall bring
the bullock unto the door of the
tabernacle before the lord and shall lay
his hand upon the bullock and kill the
bullet before the before the lord so in
other words israel wasn't really worried
about that because the temple was right
in their midst but if you're a gentile
you gotta go to the temple
you may have to travel
hundreds and hundreds of miles
wait wait there's more number three not
only was it to be done in the temple it
was to be done in jerusalem and no other
place notice deuteronomy 12 10 but when
you go over the jordan and dwell in the
land which the lord your god given you
to inherit and when he giveth you the
rest from all your enemies round about
so that you dwell on the land safely
then shall there be a place which the
lord your god shall choose to cause his
name to dwell there
this shall ye bring all that i command
you watch this you guys your burnt
offerings and your sacrifices your
tithes and your heath offerings of your
hand and all your choice vows which you
shall make unto the lord watch this and
you shall rejoice before the lord your
god you and your sons your daughters
your manservants your maidservants and
the levite that is within your gates for
as much as he has no part of the
inheritance with you take heed to
yourself that you offer not thy burnt
offering in every place that you see but
in a place which the lord shall choose
in one of those tribes therefore thou
shalt offer
thy birth offering
and there thou shalt there shalt thou do
what i command thee so in other words
beloved you couldn't be in texas
give me a one in the chat if you
understand what i just said you couldn't
be in you know in in in jamaica or
france or some other place and just be
like ah you know what i mean forgiveness
right now so let me just like throw up
an altar in my house no no no no you had
to go
think about those who lived are far off
the only way that they could get there
is that they had to travel great
distances from one nation to another
man that sounds pretty difficult y'all
how about this how about this not only
did they have to travel watch this i
need you to see this okay let's just go
back to the description for sin
was there circumcision required to keep
the law thou shalt not kill
was circumcision required
to keep that commandment
was circumcision required for a person
to
keep the commandment do not bear false
witness i want you to watch this
no
circumcision was
required to do any one of these
commandments
number two
no temple was required
to keep any of these commandments
no temple no sacrifice in order not to
steal you don't have to give a sacrifice
first and go to the temple no no no it's
just do not steal
none of these commandments
require you to go to jerusalem to keep
them
not i am the lord your god you can keep
that anywhere no idolatry you can keep
that anywhere do not take the name of
the lord in vain you can keep that
anywhere remember the sabbath keeping
holy you can keep that anywhere honor
your mother and father do not commit
adultery no murder no sin you could keep
those anywhere no sacrifice no temple no
circumcision was required to keep the
description of the law or what we call
the description of sin no no
circumcision temple sacrifice jerusalem
visit required nothing
but if you were trying to get the cure
the cure was only local so watch this
the description of sin was universal
anywhere in the world where someone
kills it is sin anywhere in the world
where someone lies it is sin anywhere in
the world where someone works with great
image it is sin but in those days the
prescription for sin was only local
meaning it was only in israel
now
watch this guys
so we've just clearly identified that
jesus that god himself put enmity
between his seed and the seed of the
devil there was a separation a
distinction and they could not get
access to forgiveness of sins unless
they were to go through that most
discouraging wall of circumcision
if you were circumcised then you could
keep the passover then you could keep
the first fruits then you could keep all
these feasts which all were connected
with sacrifices in other words were all
designed to be a part of the process of
cleansing from sin
now that's part one of the prophecy i
will put enmity between thee and the
woman now the second part of the
prophecy is i will my seed will bruise
the head of the serpent and we know this
happened at calvary matthew 27 33 and
when they were coming to a place called
golgotha is to say a place of a skull
please note here i love this
jesus died on a skull-shaped hill
remember the prophecy says that jesus
would bruise the head
of the serpent
the hill is called calvary which in the
greek is crameon
it's also called golgotha which is
literally called the place of a skull
when jesus died he was breaking the the
head this is the skull
as it were of of satan
now now watch this guys watch what
happens when jesus
dies and in essence crushes the skull of
the serpent watch what the text says
matthew 27 33
and when they were coming to a place
called golgotha that is to say the place
of a skull there it is just so you can
see it just you can have reference now
watch this jesus when he cried again
with the loud voice yielded up the ghost
and behold the veil of the temple was
rent in twain from top to bottom and the
earth did quake now let me ask you a
question y'all let me ask you a question
when the veil of the temple is rent in
two
what does that signify
what did that signify
what was shut down
come on y'all what was shut down
the place
where people went
to get cured of sin
has been shut down
god why would you do that
what are people gonna do now when they
sin
what will people do now
if they lie or steal or commit adultery
those things still exist y'all the
description for sin is the very same as
it was in the old testament
the description remains the same but
evidently god is saying i'm shutting
down the house where i used to you know
make available a cure because a new cure
is coming
and if a new cure is coming then we have
no need for the system which provided an
all cure
put a one in the chat no put a seven in
the chat y'all if y'all are catching
this right now when the temple is shut
down what god is demonstrating here is
that the prescription
is about to become universal
through the blood of christ
and beloved watch this the prescription
becoming universal does nothing to
change the description of sin the
description of sin is still the same
thing
killing in the new testament is the same
as killing in the old lying today is the
same as lying in the garden
stealing today is the same as stealing
back then the description of sin remains
the same but what jesus has come to do
away with is an in ineffective cure
the cure was only symbolic of something
that was to come in the future and that
thing that was to come in the future was
the very blood of jesus yes the vaccine
was upgraded to one that really works
are you all catching this
not only was the temple
no longer significant the temple would
be destroyed beloved in 70 a.d but not
only was the temple destroyed watch this
look at the text luke 21 24 and they
shall fall by the edge of the sword and
shall be led away captive into all
nations and jerusalem
shall be trodden down under the gentiles
until the times of the gentiles should
be fulfilled in other words not only
not only was the temple destroyed but
the city was destroyed meaning
listen guys
meaning
watch this
the
the temple
where the prescription was found and the
city where you could where the the
spirit the prescription was found both
are now destroyed
it's almost as if in christ's death the
enmity
when he bruises the head of satan he now
says okay i'm about to remove
i'm about to remove the separating wall
and now
hmm
i'm about to remove the enmity watch
this guys in galatians 5 6 15
for in christ jesus neither circumcision
availeth anything nor uncircumcision but
a new creature
circumcision is no longer required to
get access to the remedy do you
understand that
jesus christ in dying became our
circumcision
so now for the gentile who is now trying
to look for salvation guess what's been
removed he no longer has to go through
the painful process of circumcision all
he needs is a circumcision of the heart
all right how else was the enmity
removed circumcision no longer needed
watch this watch this guy's a journey to
the temple under the new covenant a
journey to the temple is no longer
needed to get access to the cure number
two our journey to jerusalem is no
longer required to get access to the
cure and number three actually number
four number one is a circumcision number
two is the journey to the temple number
three is his journey to jerusalem and
number four the cure itself has been
updated and is now universally available
how are y'all doing
are y'all getting the context
so now when we go to the new testament
and we start reading right we start
reading these verses that when we read
them out of context we're just like well
it must mean the law of god's on the way
with no no no now i understand watch
this beloved in this new system there's
a new way to get forgiveness it's no
longer circumcision it's no longer going
to the temple it's no longer going to
jerusalem now in
christ when i sin
when i lie when i steal when i commit
adultery in christ i have a new means of
forgiveness
christ hasn't done away with the
description for sin he has done away
with the prescription for sin
did y'all catch that
watch this
watch this we're about to we got a few
more texts
parts of chapters and then we're going
to be done just follow this
having therefore brethren boldness to
enter into the holiest by the blood of
jesus by a new and living way what does
that mean no longer do i need to be
circumcised no longer do i need to
travel to a temple no longer do i need
to go to jerusalem if i want to be cured
from my line and stealing no no no
there's a new way now and that new way
is through his flesh
his flesh has taken the place of that
enmity
he is conservative for us a new way
through the veil that is to say through
his flesh that means his death and
having a high priest of the house of god
let us draw near oh man
yes yes yes let us draw near
watch this guys
you could not draw near before unless
you were circumcised in heart i mean in
flesh then you could draw near remember
the text we just read it remember let's
go back to it
let's go back let's go back no it's not
there we're just going to keep moving
forward so in in other words they had to
draw in order for them to draw near they
have to be circumcised not anymore not
anymore that's been done away with
let us draw near with a true heart and
full assurance of faith having our
hearts sprinkled from an evil conscience
and our bodies washed with pure water
how about this ephesians 2 for he is our
peace who has made both one and has
broken down the middle
wall of partition between us
what was that middle wall of petition
you got to be circumcised if you want to
join us
you got to come to jerusalem if you want
to join us
you got to come to the temple if all
right you trying to say you're not the
devil's seat anymore you want to be down
with us you got to be circumcised you
got to come to jerusalem you got to come
to the temple that's what and you got to
sacrifice if you want to be down with us
jesus says no longer
i've gotten rid of that middle wall
watch this having abolis in his flesh
the enmity
did you see that
having abolished in his flesh
the what enmity the enmity back there in
genesis 3 15. i'm getting rid of it now
because i bruised the devil's head and
now i'm opening the way for everyone so
i'm getting rid of the law of
commandments contained in ordinances
this is it's the prescription of sin
that he's getting rid of
so that he can make in himself of twain
one new man and soul making peace that
he might reconcile both unto god in one
body of the cross
having slain the enmity thereby
and came and preached peace to you which
were what afar off
the devil's seed the devil's offspring
and to them that were nigh
in christ's death
he has gotten rid of the enmity that he
himself put there and said now you want
access to salvation it's all open why
because i just defeated the devil
i just defeated the devil
i'm opening up the way to salvation to
everyone so it doesn't matter if you're
in china it doesn't matter if you're in
spain it doesn't matter if you're if
you're in africa it doesn't matter if
you're an amer it doesn't matter where
you are the blood of christ is is is you
can get it anywhere
come on guys we're almost done almost
there notice ephesians 2 for by grace
for by grace are you saved through faith
and not of yourselves it is a gift of
god not of works lest any man should
boast what he's saying here in the very
same chapter is this listen
you are not saved anymore by that
circumcision of the old testament you're
no longer saved by going to the temple
and going to jerusalem no no no you are
saved by grace through faith that means
by the simple access of christ wherever
you are
when you sin
when you realize i'm i'm in sin
when you realize that the description of
sin has condemned you yes you're guilty
of sin yes you're guilty of lying yes
you're guilty of murdering yes you're
guilty of worshiping grieving images yes
you're guilty of putting other gods
before you before god when you realize
that whoa
this this is pointing to me now the cure
is in the blood of jesus the blood of
jesus forgives you of your sin it does
not wipe out what sin is let me say it
again
the blood of jesus does not nullify the
commandment that says thou shalt not
kill that doesn't make any sense why
would jesus come and get rid of the
description of the law
he came to offer a new prescription to
forgive you of your sin which sin is
defined as the breaking of the
commandments god has not gotten rid of
the law jesus has not gotten rid of the
law what he got rid of was the was the
process whereby one gains access to
forgiveness the ceremonial law has been
done away with everyone this is why
hebrews 2 14 says this for as much then
as the children are partakers of flesh
and blood he also likewise himself took
part of the same
watch this
that through death
he might destroy him that had the power
of death that is the devil
and deliver them
who through fear of death for all their
lifetime subject to bondage in other
words i'm coming to deliver the devil
seed
i'm gonna defeat the devil and then
deliver those who are under his bondage
deliver those who were of his seed but
it's only they have to make the free
will choice to do it i'm not just gonna
deliver them okay everybody save now no
no no they have to choose to be
circumcised in the heart and then this
is why the bible says now if you love me
keep my commandments i delivered you
keep my commandments he's not talking
about go sacrifice animals he's talking
about don't lie don't steal don't kill
don't commit adultery he's talking about
god so having other gods before me the
commandments of god have not changed my
my beloved christian friend
so watch this genesis 3 15 number one he
would put enmity that's the old
testament that's the ceremonial law
number two he would bruise the head of
the serpent he did that at the cross to
provide a new cure and number three he
now removes the enmity he removes the
ceremonial law that that which divided
jew from gentile and he says not in me
in me there is neither jew nor gentile
circumcision nor uncircumcision
in me
it is only christ
do y'all get it
do y'all understand what was done away
with
and what still stands
hebrews 10 1 for the law having a shadow
of good things to come and not the very
image of those things can never with
those sacrifices which they offered year
by year made the comers there unto
perfect watch this
for then would they not have ceased to
be offered because that the worshipers
once purged should have no more
conscience of sin but in those
sacrifices there is a remembrance again
made of sins every year for it is not
possible that the blood of bulls and
goats
ceremonial law that's my emphasis right
there i put that in there ceremonial law
for it it is not possible that the blood
of bull of goats the ceremonial law
should take away sins the moral law
wherefore he cometh into the world he
saved sacrifice and offering with
without thou what's not but a body has
now prepared for me
in burnt offering and sacrifices for sin
ceremonial law for moral law thou has no
pleasure then said i know i come in the
volume of the book it is written of me
to do thy will oh god above when he said
sacrifice an offering and burnt
offerings for sin thou was not neither
had pleasure therein which are offered
by the law
then said i lo i come to do thy will oh
god he taketh away the first
that's the first cure that he may
establish the second
that's the second cure wherefore the
holy ghost also is of witness to us for
after that he said before this is the
covenant i will make with them after
those days say the lord i will put my
laws into their hearts and in their
minds will i write them
[Music]
how are y'all doing
i hope this is making sense to you i got
one listen
colossians 2 this is one of the other
go-to verses listen and watch how it now
unders makes so much sense
watch what it says watch what it says
colossians 2 10 and you are completing
him which is the head and principality
of power in whom also you are
circumcised
with the circumcision made without hands
in putting off the body of the sins of
the flesh by the circumcision of christ
see that
buried with him in baptism wherein also
you are risen with him through the faith
of the operation of god who has raised
him from the dead watch this and you
being dead in your sins and the
uncircumcision of your flesh has he
quickened together with him having
forgiven all your trespasses watch this
blotting out the handwriting of
ordinances that was against us
you got to be circumcised
you have to offer these sacrifices you
have to come to the temple you have to
come to jerusalem but i live 100 miles
away doesn't matter
blotting out the handwriting of
ordinances that was against us which was
contrary to us circumcised at 20 are you
sure yes and all you and all the boys in
your house
and took that out of the way nailing
that to the cross
that's what he got rid of guys so romans
2 25 for circumcision verily profited if
you keep the law but if you be a breaker
of the law then circumcision is your
circumcision is made uncircumcision
therefore if the uncircumcision keep the
righteousness of the law shall not his
uncircumcision be counted for
circumcision
i hope y'all are catching this
i hope this is making sense john 14 15
jesus said if you love me keep my
commandments romans 13 8 oh no man
anything but to love one another for he
that loveth another has fulfilled the
law beloved the law still stands romans
39 for this thou shalt not commit
adultery thou shalt not kill thou shalt
not steal thou shalt not bear false
witness thou shalt not covet and if
there be any other commandment it is
briefly comprehended in this saying
namely thou shalt love thy neighbor as
thyself love worketh no ill to his
neighbor therefore love is the
fulfilling of the law beloved jesus said
it himself in matthew 22 the two great
commandments are to love god and to love
your neighbor as yourself and these are
not two new commandments they come from
the old testament
here's my final slide guys
my final slide
in daniel 2
you got to understand this
nebuchadnezzar is given a dream
zeonda metoo
me too
all of this gold if you understand
genesis 3 15
you have the foundation to understand
what was the enmity that was put there
and was removed and it makes clear
crystal clear what law still stands and
what law was done away with listen
nebuchadnezzar's dream he sees these
nations rising
represented by this image of a man
and then a stone that is cut out of a
mountain without hands destroys the
image on its feet
why is that significant it's it's
significant for one simple reason
not only does this stone represent
christ i want you to understand that but
there is only one other place in the
scripture where stone
cut out of a mountain without hands
occurred
and that is the law of god
that's the ten commandments
the world is on a moral decline
and it is because the world has turned
its back on the ten commandments but the
world has turned its back on the ten
commandments because they're simply
following the example of the church who
is preaching from pulpits every weekend
that the law of god that we're no longer
under great under the law we're under
grace the law has been done away with
and the and the confusing part about
this is that they will turn around and
speak to the heathen saying you must
keep the commandments of god
thou shalt not kill the law of god
hasn't changed these are not 10
suggestions either 10 commandments you
took the law out of public schools and
public places beloved listen to me the
law of god was never meant to be in
public places the law of god was meant
to be written in the heart on these
tables right here my appeal to you
you're watching this you've heard this
for the first time you didn't understand
ah man i should be keeping the law and
listen
i'm telling you you will get slack you
will get
the bible says the devil goes to make
war with those who keep the commandments
of god if you decide today i gotta keep
the commandments i don't care what my
preacher says i don't care what the law
of god still stands and i understand it
now the devil's gonna come at you best
believe that understand that but beloved
god has you
god's gonna protect you
god is gonna keep you
and so i'm appealing to you as you as
you listen to this go back and search
the scriptures for yourself and see if
what i said is so search the scriptures
and beloved
when the spirit of god shows you truth
i i implore you to follow it
i implore you to follow it
so please put a one in the chat if this
made sense to you just
just put a one in the chat if this made
sense to you
i'm gonna this
every
end of the month at the end of the month
i'm gonna be preaching another message
that is gonna connect with what you
heard today it's going to be all
doctrinal so i'm doing this once a month
by the grace of god if you're looking
for truth if you've been confused about
certain things and you're looking for
truth i i would encourage you to tune in
because you're not going to want to miss
these okay
i want you to pray with me heavenly
father
today there are those who are struggling
with what they've heard because they
have heard truth
and now they're wondering what to do
with it
lord i pray that your spirit
would guide them
would strengthen them would encourage
them
would give them holy boldness
lord we give them understanding the
understanding that you've given them
today lord give them the courage to walk
out to step out on that understanding
and to do as you have said if you love
me keep my commandments held them to
understand that the law of god
that was written with your own finger
is not done away but that is the
description of sin what jesus christ
came to abolish was the old cure and
replace it with something that is
universally available please lord it's
that simple it's that simple
so lord help us to grasp this truth
because if we can grasp this truth then
the other truths that are to follow will
be easy to understand and everything
will begin to make sense and so that i'm
praying for those who are watching this
now and those who will watch this by
faith in the future
please
let your spirit attend them as they
listen
and may conviction take over their
hearts is my prayer in jesus name
amen
and amen
i want to thank you guys for tuning in
to this if you're watching this for the
first time whether you're watching this
live now or you're watching it in the
future and you want to get more
information pastor i need more
understanding on this law of god thing
i'm going to encourage you to email the
church okay specifically you can email
patrice at livingmana
dot live and she will get the email
either to me or to rick our bible worker
and we will follow up on it okay
so god bless you uh i want to encourage
those of you that are on who want to
stay on a stay after for the altar live
we'll put the alter live link up in the
in the chat uh there it is if you want
to get on for the after discussion
please feel free to join us there and uh
you guys be blessed uh and i will see
you
next week
god bless